Guide to the Black Metal Music collection, 1985-2008.
Black Metal Music collection
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Black Metal Music collection, 1985-2008.
8031
Johan, Kugelberg
3 cubic feet.
Audio Recordings, Memorabilia, Printed Materials
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Original fanzines, magazines, sound recordings, photographs, and posters documenting Black Metal music.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Original fanzines, magazines, sound recordings, photographs, and posters documenting Black Metal music, including the production files for the book "True Norwegian black metal: we turn in the night consumed by fire" with photographs by Peter Beste.
6 vinyl records by Ulver/Mysticum, Burzum, Abruptum, and Mayhem.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Kugelberg, Johan,; Beste, Peter.
Subjects:
Black metal (Music).; Black metal (Music); Satanism in music.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Fanzines & Magazines
Boxes 1-5
Series II. Video & Audio Recordings
Boxes 6-7
Series III. Manuscript/ Typescprit & Ephemera
Box 8
Series IV. Printed Ephemera & T-Shirts
Boxes 8-9
Series V. True Norwegian Black Metal production materials
Boxes 10-13, mapcase
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Fanzines & Magazines
  - Slayer, 1985 - 2004? (Box 1)
    14 issues
  - Aberration, ca. 1994? (Box 2)
    1 issue
  - Ancient Ceremonies, 1998-2003 (Box 2)
    3 issues
  - Antithesis Megazine, 1998 (Box 2)
  - Avalanche Magazine, 1995 (Box 2)
  - Bast Magazine, ca. 2005 (Box 2)
  - Black Flame, 2000 (Box 2)
  - Bloodshed, 1993 (Box 2)
  - Calmant, 1996 (Box 2)
  - Chainletter, ca. 1994? (Box 2)
  - Chaos, 1997-1999 (Box 2)
  - Chord, late 1990s? (Box 2)
  - Corpse Gristle, late 1990s? (Box 2)
  - Cycle of Flesh, 1996? (Box 2)
  - Dark Shivers, 1993? (Box 2)
  - Descent, 1997 (Box 2)
    1 issue (2 copies)
  - Eclipse, late 1990s? (Box 2)
    3 issues (two duplicates)
  - Goats of Pandemonium, 1994 (Box 2)
  - Grimoire of Exalted Deeds, ca. 1997-2000 (Box 2)
    5 issues (10, 13, 14, 16, 23)
  - Hellfrost, 1996-1999 (Box 3)
    3 issues (one duplicate)
  - Helvete Katalog, 1992-1993 (Box 3)
    2 issues Catalog from the store Helvete, owned by Euronymous (of Mayhem)
  - Highwire Dze, 1999 (Box 3)
  - Lachrymose Zine, mid-1990s? (Box 3)
  - Legacy, 1999-2001 (Box 3)
  - Mandrake Magazine, 2000-2001 (Box 3)
    2 issues
  - Metal-Core, 1998 (Box 3)
  - Mysticism Magazine, late 1990s? (Box 3)
  - Nagual, 1994 (Box 3)
  - Nekrologium, 1996 (Box 3)
  - NGF, 1994? (Box 4)
  - Nocturnal, 1994 (Box 4)
  - Oskorei Magazine, 1999 (Box 4)
  - Petrified 'Zine, 1993 (Box 4)
  - Promethean Crusade, ca. 1997 (Box 4)
  - Requiem, ca. 1993-1997 (Box 4)
  - Sloth, 1999 (Box 4)
  - Transcending the Mundane, ca. 1998 (Box 4)
  - View into the Abyss, 1993-1994 (Box 4)
  - Kerrang!, 1993 - 1994 (Box 5)
    9 issues + (1 duplicate) - Their complete contemporary coverage of Mayhem- and Burzum-related crimes.
  - Arkitip, ca. 2005? (Box 5)
    1 issue - Peter Beste issue packaged with a T-Shirt
  - Bant, ca. 2006? (Box 5)
    1 issue (#35, Peter Beste cover story)
  - Hit List, 1999 (Box 5)
    #1; Black Metal cover story
  - Photocopied articles on black metal, n/a (Box 5)
    3 articles from mainstream pulications
- Series II. Video & Audio Recordings
  - Side A: Ulver, "Ulverytternes"; Side B: Mysticum, "Mourning" 7" vinyl record, 1993; SR-6350 (Box 6)
  - Burzum, "Aske" 12" vinyl record, 1993; SR-6351 (Box 6)
  - Abruptum, "Obscuritatem advoco amplectère me" 12" vinyl record, 1993; SR-6352 (Box 6)
  - Mayhem, "De Mysteriis Dom Sathanas" 12" vinyl record, 1994; SR-6353 (Box 6)
  - Mayhem, "Deathcrush" 12" vinyl record, includes inserts, 1987; SR-6354; Label: Posercorpse Music (Box 6)
  - Mayhem, "Deathcrush" 12" vinyl record, 1993; SR-6355; Label: Deathlike Silence Productions (Box 6)
  - Embrace the Hate, ca. 1999 (Box 7)
    6 volume VHS videorecording
  - Black Metal: Norsk Metal Documentary, n/a (Box 7)
    DVD Documentary
  - Abruptum: From Hell, 2002 (Box 7)
    Bootleg cassete w/book
  - CDs, 1993 - 2006? (Box 7)
    7 CDs by Mayhem, Satyricom, Sigh, Absalom, Ulver
- Series III. Manuscript/ Typescript & Ephemera
  - Original Euronymous material, ca. 1990 - 1992 (Box 8)
    2 Letters (typescript w/ manuscript signatures), w/ English Translations; 1 Audio cassette (in envelope w/ manuscript) sent to It (of Abruptum) containing early rough mixes of Mayhem music.
  - Original Dead materials, 1992? (Box 8)
    1 Mayhem flyer w/ Dead manuscript
  - Original Vesa Iitti Materials, 1991 (Box 8)
    1 Letter from Vesa Iitti (of Xysma?) to "Jon" (Metalion): typescript w/ manuscript signature
  - Related Typescript, ca. 2005 (Box 8)
    1 Letter from "Warren" to Johan Kugelberg
  - Photocopied Euronymous material, ca. 1991 - 1992 (Box 8)
    6 Photocopied letters, 4 in English, 2 in Norwegian (w/ English translations attached)
  - Photocopied Dead Materials, ca. 1991 (Box 8)
    1 six page manuscript document, 4 letters, 2 drawings, 1 funeral card
  - Hváll typescript, ca. 2005 (Box 8)
    1 printed e-mail from Hváll (Jarle Kvåle of Windir to Peter Beste)
  - Rock Ministries, 1989 (Box 8)
    Photocopied letter on Satanic metal from Jeff L. Godwin of "Rock Ministries" to "Reuben"
  - Photocopied black metal ephemera (Box 8)
    Photocopies of letters and assorted ephemera in the collection
  - Digitized black metal ephemera (Box 8)
    Two DVD-ROMS containing scanned letters and assorted ephemera in the collection
  - Black Metal pioneer photos, ca. 1988 - 1993 (Box 8)
    100 4x6 prints of Black Metal Pioneers
- Series IV. Printed Ephemera & T-Shirts
  - Posters & flyers, ca. 1991 - 2006 (Box 8)
    8 Posters, fliers & press releases
  - 2004 Black Metal calendar, 2004 (Box 9)
    Calendar using Peter Beste images
  - T-Shirts, ca. 2004 (Box 9)
    3 Peter Beste T-Shirts
- Series V. True Norwegian Black Metal production materials
  - True Norwegian Black Metal Binder proofs, ca. 2007 (Box 10)
    2 proofs of True Norwegian Black Metal by Peter Beste in black binders
  - True Norwegian Black Metal mockup, 2008 (Box 11)
    1 full-size, hardcover mockup with 2 prototype slipcases. This is a blank prototype of the size and page count of the final book, with 4x6 prints tipped in and many manuscript notes.
  - True Norwegian Black Metal promotional material, 2008 (Box 12)
    postcards, presskit, prospectus
  - True Norwegian Black Metal proof pages, 2008 (Box 13)
    Additional loose proof pages of True Norwegian Black Metal
  - Production materials & Miscellaneous, 2008 (Box 13)
    Used transfer lettering & mockups of promotional material
  - Metalion text drafts, 2007 (Box 13)
    2 drafts of Metalion text
  - Johan Kugelberg drafts, ca. 2007 - 2008 (Box 13)
    2 Drafts of Johan Kugelberg text
  - True Norwegian Black Metal notes, ca. 2007 - 2008 (Box 13)
    Assorted notes & interview quotes for True Norwegian Black Metal text
  - Ephemera & fanzine photocopies, ca. 2007 - 2008 (Box 13)
    Photocopies of fanzine pages and ephemera used in production of True Norwegian Black Metal text
  - Unpublished Peter Beste Images, ca. 2002 - 2007 (Box 13)
    42 4x6 prints of images not used in True Norwegian Black Metal
  - DVD-ROM of notes for True Norwegian Black Metal, ca. 2003 - 2007 (Box 13)
    DVD-ROM of preliminary images, notes, and other materials for True Norwegian Black Metal
  - Large-format materials, 2007 - 2008 (Mapcase-folder 1)
    Large-format Peter Beste proofs; 2007 New York Times article on Enslaved